<lesson>
  <section id="introduction">
    <h1>Introduction</h1>
    <content>
      <p>
        Programming is the act of writing instructions that a computer can follow to perform a task.
      </p>
      <p>
        It’s how we tell machines what to do, when to do it, and how to do it — using a language they understand
      </p>
    </content>
  </section>
  <section id="why-learn-programming">
    <h1>Why Learn Programming?</h1>
    <content>
        <ul>
            <li>To automate repetitive tasks</li>
            <li>To build websites, games, or apps</li>
            <li>To solve real-world problems using code</li>
            <li>To understand how technology works</li>
        </ul>
    </content>
  </section>
  <section id="how-it-works">
    <h1>How It Works</h1>
    <content>
    <p
            >Computers don’t “think” the way we do. They follow step-by-step instructions precisely — even if it results in something incorrect.</p>
        <p>That’s why code must be:</p>
        <ul>
            <li><b>Clear</b>: easy for humans to read ;</li>
            <li><b>Precise</b>: detailed enough for machines to follow ;</li>
            <li><b>Logical</b>: follows a correct flow.</li>
        </ul>
        <p
            >Programmings write their code in a programming language. There are many programming languages to choose from, each with its own strengths and weaknesses. Some popular languages include Python, Java, JavaScript, C++, and Ruby. Each language has its own syntax, features, and use cases.</p>
        <p>An example of code is below which outputs <code
                >"Hello World!"</code> to the <definition
                    word="console"
                    meaning="the console is essentially an output log of human-readable text."
                >console</definition>.</p>
        <code-block lang="javascript">
            console.log("Hello World!");
        </code-block>
    </content>
  </section>
  <section id="programming-vs-coding">
    <h1>Programming v. Coding</h1>
    <content>
        <p
            >These terms are often used interchangeably, but they’re not exactly the same:</p>
            <table>
                <tr>
                    <th>Term</th>
                    <th>Description</th>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>Coding</td>
                    <td>Writing lines of code using a programming language</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>Programming</td>
                    <td
                    >Designing the logic, structure, and flow of a solution before writing code</td>
                </tr>
            </table>
            <p
            >Overall, coding is part of programming — but programming also involves <b
                >thinking</b>, <b>planning</b>, and <b>problem-solving</b>.</p>
                <summary>
                <p>
                    <b
                    >Analogy: </b> Programming is like building a house. Coding is like laying the bricks and mortar, while programming is like designing the blueprint and planning the layout.
                </p>
                </summary>
    </content>
  </section>
</lesson>
